## **David Trail**

CONTACT 11/6 Watson Crescent Mobile: +44 7816 930 167

INFORMATION Edinburgh Email: mr.dj.trail@gmail.com EH11 1HB DoB: 8th of January 1990

Diffi fild Dob. Our of Sandary 1930

ABOUT ME

My ideal role is as a Linux sysadmin, I ran my first shared hosting based website more than a decade ago and since then have come on leaps and bounds to the point where I've been administering dedicated, VPS and AWS cloud servers for many years. It's what I've found myself enjoying more than any other area of informatics.

I use Linux daily both professionally for contracted clients and past full-time positions as well as for myself (I have OpenVPN, Nginx, Exim, Squid and dnsmasq/dnscrypt on my own personal VPS).

I am confident in my C/C++ abilities and completely fluent in Perl, Python, Bash and SQL (as well as PostgreSQL/MySQL administration) and on top of this I have a background in Computer Science which allows me to understand perfectly what's going on at a code level.

#### Work history

## Freelance Linux System Administrator

September 2014 until today

- Repeat contracts for numerous clients generally in the area of Linux DevOps/sysadmin/software engineering
- Technologies include: Docker, Qemu/KVM, OpenVPN, Puppet, Python, Perl, Bash, AWS (Cloud Formation, EC2, S3, ...), Cloud-Flare, Git, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Nginx/Apache/uwsgi, etc
- Duties include: migration, configuration and set-up, security, service optimisation, monitoring, benchmarking, auto-scaling, networking, . . .

Client: Leo Hämäläinen

- Leo has been my client for the past  $\approx 7$  months
- I have been contracted as a Linux sysadmin for their operations at devoca.fi, a backend for their hand-held label device and other products with hundreds of clients throughout Finland and elsewhere who rely on Devoca's servers to operate
- Duties have included: Upscaling operations; troubleshooting downtime; eradicating a rootkit that they'd contracted under a previous contractor; optimising both Apache and MySQL's configurations; planning for minimal downtime during migration periods; masterslave MySQL mirroring; backup script writing

- Technologies include: Apache Servermix, Apache HTTP, Exim mail server (MTA), Ubuntu 14.04, iptables firewall, fail2ban, MySQL, DKIM + SPF, DNS
- Communication has been key to my success in this role

#### Client: CloudWorks

- I was contracted to set up a continuous deployment strategy utilising AWS's Cloud Formation, EC2 and RDS alongside a Puppet master server to manage the deployed servers. This required writing from scratch a Cloud Formation script with a variable number of EC2 instances which would image themselves from an AMI which would connect to a Puppet master server and auto-configure themselves with an app hosted on Github.
- This has been the most challenging but also most enjoyable role I have done so far. Working within Linux, AWS and DevOps is where I feel completely at home and find myself loving the work that I do, impressing myself with my own abilities.
- Technologies: AWS, EC2, RDS, Route53, Puppet, PostgreSQL, troposphere, cloud-config, Cloud Formation

#### Freelance Software Engineer

July 2013 to September 2014 (1 year 2 months)

- Several large projects using Django + Python
- Web development
- $\bullet$  Postgres + MySQL
- Bitcoin trading, investment and development
- Linux system administration

# Client: Éric Bisceglia

- Worked with Éric and another software engineer for  $\approx 6$  months
- Containerising app instances to provide security in case of a security breach, ensuring uptime and redundancy for the web frontend/PostgreSQL backend on Microsoft's Azure platform

## Software Engineer, Scotweb

June 2011 to July 2013 (2 years 1 month)

- Commercial web development and maintenance
- Linux system administration
- Twisted Python / Python development
- Full stack deployment and configuration
- Web development (HTML/CSS/jQuery)

#### Village Orderly, Aberdeenshire council

July 2007 to September 2010 (3 years, 2 months)

#### Kitchen Porter, Valentinos restaurant

June 2004 to June 2006 (2 years)

### **EDUCATION**

## Computer Science BSc, **Heriot-Watt University** September 2007 to May 2011

$2^{\rm nd}$ year	3 <sup>rd</sup> year	4 <sup>th</sup> year
Database Management	Artificial Intelligence	Distributed Systems
Discreet Mathematics	Operating Systems	Parallel Technologies
Internet Communications	Computer Graphics	Data Mining
Software Design	Professional Development	Machine Learning
Formal Specifications	Concurrency	Biological computation

## OTHER

- Achieved Intermediate 1 Spanish (Escuela de Idiomas)
- $\bullet$  Raised £1,050 for MND Scotland in a charity Skydive
- Maintain Github and Bitbucket profiles
- Always up to date with the latest technologies in DevOps and Software Engineering

Name	Dr. Greg Michaelson	Mr. Steve Tuttle
Relation	Project supervisor	Client (DevOps, AWS)
Email	G.Michaelson@hw.ac.uk	swt@drinkme.com
Phone	$+44\ 131\ 451\ 3422$	$+61\ 400\ 601\ 689$